Once you are satisfied with the
content structure and layout of your
presentation, you may wish to add
some animation or transition effects.
This will just enhance the appearance
of the presentation when it is
being presented to an audience.
So at the moment, I don't
have any animations or
transitions on the presentation.
And if I go to the slideshow view and
select play from start, you will see
that the first slide appears instantly.
And then as I click, each slide simply
comes onto the screen instantly.
And every time I click.
So to make some changes to that I'd
like to add a transition effect so that
each of the slides, as it comes on the
screen, it comes in in a certain manner
rather than just appearing all at once.
So I'm going to add the
transition effects to that.
So if I click on the transitions tab
and as you can see along the top of the
transition there are a range of transition
effects that you can select from.
So if you click on one, it
will demonstrate how that
will apply to the slide.
So then you can go through until
you find one that you are happy
with, and then you can apply that.
And I'm going to go with
the split transition.
And now I can go on to slide two,
three, four, and five, and apply
different transitions to each slide.
However, just for consistency, I do have
the option to apply that to all by just
clicking on that button there in the
top right corner, I click apply to all.
That has now applied that same
transition to all of the slides.
So if we just demo that by going to
slideshow and then select play from start.
Every time I click, as you can
see the slides come in slightly
different rather than instantly
they come in a certain manner.
So again, but if you're not happy with
the transition that you've applied,
you can always go back in and make
a change and select another one.
So once you're happy with your
transition, there are another couple of
tools that you could use within here.
You can time the actual
transition, so specify the
transition duration in seconds.
So if you want the transition
to take longer, you can
increase the time on there.
Again.
There's also on mouse clicks or
the transition only occurs when I
click the mouse so that slide will
stay on the screen until I click.
And also you can add a sound, a transition
sound so you can click on there and
you could have applause, arrow, bomb.
So you could select a sound effect
to appear with the transition.
And I'll just have a quick
demonstration of that with applause.
So if we preview that.
And as you can see, you can have a full,
so we'll just go with no sound for that.
So now that I'm happy with the
transitions, it's time to think
about adding some animations.
So again, if I click on the animations
tab and as you can see they are all
greyed out at the moment, and I'm
just going to click on slide one.
And the reason that all of the animation
effects are greyed out is that they will
not become active until you select an
element within the slide to animate.
And as soon as I click on the first
piece of text, they all become active.
And then again, as with the
transitions I can just go through and
select the animation I wish to use.
And I think I will go for the grow
and turn and I've applied that.
So as you can see, there's
a number one appeared.
That means that I have applied
the animation to that text.
Every element within the
slide can be animated.
So I'm going to animate the first
picture of the balloon and I'm going
to do a checkerboard with that again
I can click on the next image in
the slide and select dissolve in.
The sales report, I'm going to
go back and do the grow and turn.
So once I'm happy with that I can preview
that slide to see how it will look.
So that is how the slide will appear.
When I actually do the presentation.
It can then go on to add animations
to each element within there.
So you can add animations to the chart.
The text within there, all of the
title text ,the table so any element
within a presentation can be animated.
One of the things that you need
to be aware of, is that by default
it will automatically set it so
the animations appear on click.
So when you run the slideshow
you will have to click through.
So if you've got a lot of animations
that can take some time and detract
from your work or your focus
on exactly what you're doing.
So you're presenting it.
You would rather have it come in
automatically that can be changed.
If you look up on the right-hand side,
the animations pane has appeared.
So if I look along here, I can see the
animations that have been applied and they
are all selecting are all showing a little
mouse cursor which means a click, so every
time I click the animation will appear.
I can change that by selecting
from here "after previous".
So now a little clock appears.
And again, I can select after
previous and again, after previous,
and again, after previous.
You can also select the
duration of the animation.
So if I want the animation to take
longer, I can increase the timing on that.
So just for example, I take
that up to two seconds.
And for the second one, I'll take
that up to three, 2.5 seconds.
The third one, I'll take up to three
and I'll leave the last one alone.
You also have the effect options.
So there's various tools you
can play around within there.
The timings, again, the triggers is, was
the as part of a click sequence on click
and the text animations, you can have
the text animate, come in all at once.
So you can have a look at those tools.
And if I just preview this now, so
if I look at slide one now, as you
can see, the time for each animation
to appear is slightly different.
So as I say, you can then go through
each of the slides, add animation
as required and decide on how long
you want the animation to appear for
or how long, whether it's on click
or whether it's just automatic.